# **Jose Solis**

San Pedro, CA | +1 714-742-3311 | jasolisdev@gmail.com | josesolis.dev

### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Experienced IT professional with strong technical skills and a background in leadership and customer service.

Possessing strong communication, problem-solving and time management skills. I thrive in fast-paced environments and excel at analyzing data, interpret results, and make informed decisions.

### **EDUCATION**

Ocean View High School Huntington Beach, CA

High School Diploma Graduation Date: Jun 2012

Orange Coast College Costa Mesa, CA

Computer Science Certificate of Achievement Graduation Date: Jun 2019

California School of Health Sciences

ECG Monitor Tech Certification Graduation Date: Feb 2024

### **SKILLS**

BLS/CPR Certified, Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint), Verbal and Written Communication, Fluent in English and Spanish, Customer Service. Certificate of Specialization in C++ Programming Language.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Amazon Huntington Beach, CA

Logistic Driver Nov 2017 - Present

- Streamlined delivery process by optimizing routes based on traffic patterns and customer locations, resulting in a 15% increase in fuel efficiency and a 20% decrease in average delivery times.
- Achieved a perfect safety record over 900 days by consistently following all traffic laws and completing daily pretrip inspection checklists with 100% accuracy, ensuring the safe transportation of goods to over 1000 customers.
- Utilized exceptional communication skills to gather detailed delivery instructions from various sources, ensuring accurate and timely deliveries that met customer expectations.

Walmart Huntington Beach, CA

Supervisor Nov 2014 - Nov 2017

- Direct and supervise employees engaged in inventory management.
- Communicating business needs to salaried managers, managing and allocating resources to
- optimize efficiency.
- Supervised backroom infrastructure in order to maximize time and work efficiency.
- Contribute to the hiring process, interview and evaluate candidates

## **Full-Stack Web Developer**

**Huntington Beach, CA** 

Anaheim, CA

Freelance Jun 2019 - Present

- Freelance web developer responsible for marketing, selling services, managing all client relationships, and designing/developing websites and web-based applications for small to large businesses
- Handling all verbal and written communications between hosting companies, clients, and vendors.
- Meeting with the prospective clients to review website, and gather the client's specifications for new
- or existing websites
- Applied extensive search engine optimization principles and social media to enhance page ranking on Google and
  other search engines across a variety of keywords that drive traffic to produce profits.